Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- LaborFest Archived Website, Aug 23, 2012 - ongoing; Labor Fest
  LaborFest, established in 1994, is a labor, cultural, and film festival held annually in July in San Francisco. The festival was established in honor of the “Bloody Thursday" event and longshoremen and maritime workers strike in 1934. The website features schedules, videos, images, and other information on the current and previous years’ events. The website contains a schedule of events, which include film screenings, concerts, talks, and walking tours. The website also contains links and other multimedia.
  Labor |x History.
- LaborNet Archived Website, Jul 14, 2011 - ongoing; LaborNet (U.S.)
  LaborNet, founded in 1991, is an organization created to build a democratic communication network for the labor movement and rebuild the labor movement with new technology. LaborNets are also established in the United Kingdom, Austria, Germany, Korea, Turkey, and Japan. LaborNet also works to defend the Internet from censorship and the privatization of information that would limit and destroy the rights to communicate and build world unionism. The website aggregates news related to the labor movement.
  Labor and the Internet.; Labor |z United States |v Newspapers.
- LaborTech Archived Website, Nov 18, 2010 - ongoing; LaborTech.net
  LaborTech brings together labor video, computer, and media activists to build and develop labor communications in technology and media. The website holds conferences (the first held in 1990) and campaigns to strengthen the labor movement.
  Labor and the Internet.; Labor |z United States.
- Low Pay is Not OK Archived Website, Aug 29, 2013-Sep 6, 2014; Low Pay is Not OK.
  Formed in 2013, Low Pay is Not Ok is a labor campaign for fast food workers to raise earnings in the fast food industry to a living wage. The campaign calls for a raise to $15 an hour and the right to unionize without retaliation from employers. The campaign organizes periodic strikes and hosts a petition on their website. The website also contains strike resources.
- Manumit School (1924-1957) Archived Website, Sep 2, 2009 - ongoing; Manumit Association.
  The Manumit School was an experimental boarding school in Pawling NY. Founded on purchased farm land in 1924 by William and Helen Fincke, it was formally call the Manumit School for Workers’ Children. An early promotional flyer for the school asked parents if they’d like their children to grow up “to become men and women who can think for themselves, stand on their own two feet and fight injustice and oppression. “ It’s teachings were meant to provide a “progressive “ “workers education" slant during a time of increasing socialist optimism in America. In 1944 the school moved to Bensalem Township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania. The school closed in 1957. This website is an informational website.
  Progressive education |z New York (State).; Working class--Education--New York (State)
- Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association (MEBA) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2009 - ongoing; Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association (MEBA)
  The Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association (MEBA) is the oldest maritime trade union in the United States still currently in existence, established in 1875. MEBA primarily represents licensed mariners, especially deck and engine officers working in the United States Merchant Marine aboard U.S.-flagged vessels. It is a member union of the AFL–CIO. MEBA officers work in both the oceans and the Great Lakes in many settings, including on container ships, tankers (including LNG carriers), cruise ships, drillships, tugboats, ferries, and fireboats, as well as in various capacities in the shore side ship transport and marine industries and on government-contracted ships of the United States Maritime Administration's Ready Reserve Force and United States Navy's Military Sealift Command.
  Merchant mariners |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Metro New York Labor Communications Council Archived Website, May 13, 2010 - ongoing; Metro NY Labor Communications Council
  The Metro New York Labor Communications Council (Metro), established in 1974, is a council which consists of editors, writers, artists, photographers, graphic designers, web designers, radio program producers, labor public relations specialists, and video producers from public and private sector trade unions, related organizations, and others in the labor movement. Metro provides a forum to exchange ideas and information and to discuss the problems and questions that confront labor communicators in their work. The Council offers skills orientated workshops, seminars, journalism awards, and an annual convention to discuss relevant issues regarding the labor movement. Metro is affiliated with the International Labor Communications Association of the AFL-CIO, and cooperates with the New York City Central Labor Council.
  Central labor councils.; Labor journalism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor unions and mass media |z New York (State); Labor unions |x Public relations |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Million Worker March Movement Archived Website, Jul 20, 2011 - Feb 11, 2013; Million Worker March Movement
  The Million Worker March was a rally on October 17, 2004 on in Washington DC. The rally was against perceived attacks on the working class families. Approximately 10000 people marched on Washington.
  Demonstrations |z United States.; Labor unions |z United States.; Working class |z United States.
- National Adjunct Walkout Day, Feb 18, 2009 - ongoing
- National Air Traffic Controllers Association (NATCA) Archived Website, Dec 5, 2009 - ongoing; National Air Traffic Controllers Association (NATCA)
  National Air Traffic Controllers Association (NATCA) represents over 20,000 controllers, engineers and other safety-related professionals, including engineers, traffic management coordinators and staff specialists, with membership from every state, territory and possession of the United States. Certified in 1987, NATCA is affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  Air traffic controllers|x Labor unions |z United States.
- National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians Archived Website, Mar 15, 2009 - ongoing; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians.
  National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians-Communications Workers of America (NABET-CWA), founded in 1934, is a Union of workers who are employed in the broadcasting, distributing, telecasting, recording, cable, video, sound recording and related industries in North America. NABET-CWA has contracts with ABC, NBC, FOX and other networks, as well as local TV stations across the country and members include engineers, photographers, editors, directors, technicians, graphic artists, traffic coordinators, clerical workers, truck operators, writers, reporters, anchors, producers and others in the television and cable industry. The website includes news and event listings, their newsletters, training materials, and audiovisual materials.
- National Association of Letter Carriers (NALC) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; National Association of Letter Carriers (U.S.)
  The National Association of Letter Carriers (NALC) is an American labor union, representing non-rural letter carriers employed by the United States Postal Service. It was founded in 1889.
  Letter carriers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Postal service |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- National Domestic Workers Alliance Archived Website, Oct 26, 2011 - ongoing; The National Domestic Workers Alliance
  Founded in 2007, the National Domestic Workers Alliance organizes domestic workers in the United States to improve their living and working conditions, win respect and justice from employers and government for exploited domestic workers; challenge racism and sexism; end the exclusion of domestic workers from recognition and protection; and build a movement of migrant workers to fight the labor displacement and exploitation created by globalization.
  Household employees |z United States.
- National Education Association Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; National Educational Association.
  The National Education Association (NEA), founded in 1857, is the largest professional organization and largest labor union in the United States, representing public school teachers and other support personnel, faculty and staffers at colleges and universities, retired educators, and college students preparing to become teachers. The NEA has 3.2 million members and is headquartered in Washington, D.C. It has affiliate organizations in every state and in more than 14,000 communities across the United States.
- National Guestworker Alliance Archived Website, May 11, 2012 - ongoing; National Guestworker Alliance
  National Guestworker Alliance, founded in 2005 as the Alliance of Guestworkers, is a membership organization of guestworkers and organizes members in labor camps across the United States to win collective dignity at work. They also work to gain fairness in the terms of migration and partner with local workers to strengthen U.S. social movements for racial and economic justice. The website contains information on guestworker rights, news, and current programs.
  Foreign workers.
- National Labor College Archived Website, May 12, 2012 - ongoing; National Labor College
  National Labor College (NLC), located in Silver Spring, MD, is the only accredited higher education institution in the United States devoted exclusively to educating union members, leaders, and staff. It was established as a training center by the AFL-CIO in 1969 to strengthen union member education and organizing skills. The website contains information on admissions, academic programs, alumni, blogs, conference services and their online campus.
  Labor |x Education.
- National Mobilization Against Sweatshops Archived Website, Sep 26, 2007 - ongoing; National Mobilization Against Sweatshops.
  The National Mobilization Against Sweatshops is a grassroots educational campaign dedicated to ending sweatshop conditions for all working people. It was founded in New York City in 1996. The site includes transcripts of several oral histories of sweatshop workers.
  Sweatshops--New York (State)--New York.; Sweatshops--United States.
- National Nurses United Archived Website, Jan 15, 2010 - ongoing; National Nurses United
  National Nurses United, with more than 150,000 members from across the country, is the largest union and professional association of registered nurses in America. Founded in December 2009, NNU brought together the California Nurses Association/National Nurses Organizing Committee, United American Nurses, and Massachusetts Nurses Association. Its purpose is to give registered nurses a national voice and organizing power. It is also affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  Nurses |x Labor unions |z United States.
- National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320 Archived Website, Jan 29, 2009 - ongoing; National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320.
  The National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320, represents the majority of those who work in federally-funded legal services programs across the United States. The local also represents workers in other types of law offices, various human services programs and other agencies. The website includes new listings, strike listings, meeting information, and other information.
  Legal services |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- National Postal Mail Handlers Union Archived Website, Apr 25, 2012 - ongoing; National Postal Main Handlers Union
  The National Postal Mail Handlers Union, affiliated with the AFL-CIO and LIUNA, is the is the exclusive bargaining agent for 47,000 mail handlers who load, unload, prepare, sort, and containerize mail for the US Postal Service. The website contains news, multimedia, legislatives action alerts, and contract updates.
- National Writers Union Archived Website, Dec 8, 2012 - ongoing; National Writers Union, Local 1981
  The National Writers Union (NWU) represents freelance writers throughout the United States. It was formed in 1981 during the Writers' Congress held in New York City. In 1981, the NWU affiliated with the United Auto Workers (UAW) as Local 1981. As of 2011, the NWU has over 1,500 members in fifteen locals. The website contains news and chapter information.
  Authors |x Labor unions.
- New York Building Congress Archived Website, Mar 14, 2009 - ongoing; New York Building Congress.
  The New York Building Congress, founded in 1921, is a coalition of 400 constituent organizations comprising more than 250,000 skilled trades people and professionals that works to advance economic and infrastructure investment and job creation. The Congress publishes reports and analysis related to building projects in New York City. The Congress also created the New York Building Foundation, which promotes research, education, and philanthropy in the construction industry. The website contains reports, committee and council information, and event listings.
  Building trades |z New York (State) |z New York.; Construction industry |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor-management committees--New York (State)--New York.
- New York Chapter of the National Writers Union, Local 1981 Archived Website, Feb 6, 2009 - ongoing; National Writers Union, Local 1981
  The National Writers Union, UAW Local 1981, is a labor union for freelance writers. The NWU advocates for writers' rights and fights to improve the income, contracts and working conditions for all freelance writers, including journalists, book authors, business and technical writers, essayists, poets, playwrights, script writers, writers for the web and campus writers. The NWU, founded in 1981, consists of 16 chapters throughout the country.
  Journalists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor unions |x Screenwriters |z United States.
- New York City District Council of Carpenters. Local 157, Mar 14, 2014-ongoing; Musumeci, John
  This is the website for the New York City District Council of Carpenters, Local 157. The site was created as a blog by John Musumeci in 2007 when Local 157 was placed under emergency supervision by General President Douglas McCarron. Musumeci posts news related to the union and moderates a message board for union members. The website contains reports by the review officer for the union, delegate meeting reports, financial reports, information on delegates, by-laws, and other news sources.
  New York City District Council of Carpenters. Local 157..; Carpenters |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health Archived Website, Apr 16, 2009 - ongoing; New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health.
  New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH), founded in 1980, is a non-profit coalition of 200 local unions and more than 400 individual workers, physicians, lawyers and other health and safety activists dedicated to the right of worker safety on the job. NYCOSH operates throughout New York City, Long Island and the Lower Hudson Valley. The website gives information and assistance for those injured on the job and other training and safety resources.
  Industrial hygiene |z New York (State) |z New York; Industrial safety |z New York (State) |z New York
- New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Archived Website, Mar 14, 2009 - ongoing; New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council.
  Founded in the 1930s, The New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council, AFL-CIO (Hotel Trades Council), is the union of hotel workers in New York City. The Council represents approximately 30,000 non-managerial employees working in all hotel departments, including: housekeeping, public space, dining room, banquet, room service, kitchen, stewarding, bar, mini-bar, audio-visual, front desk, reservations, PBX, bell and door services, concierge, night auditing, laundry, valet, engineering, maintenance, electrical, carpentry, painting, upholstery, business centers, night cleaning, health spas, security, garage, purchasing and receiving, and storeroom in over 300 hotels in the New York City area. It is affiliated with the SEIU, UNITE-HERE, OPEIU, IUOE, IBEW, IUPAT, and USWA.
  Central labor councils.; Hospitality industry |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- New York Labor History Association Archived Website, May 1, 2009 - ongoing; New York Labor History Association.
  New York Labor History Association (NYLHA) was founded in 1976 by trade unionists, academics, students, archivists, educators, labor editors, attorneys, and retirees, mostly from New York State. NYLHA encourages the study of workers and their organizations and serves as a bridge between past and present labor unionists and academics. The website includes news and event listings, labor history resources, and prize winners.
  Labor |z New York (State) |x History |x Societies, etc.
- New York Metro Area Postal Workers Union, Local 10, Nov 1, 2013-ongoing; National Federation of Post Office Clerks. Local 10 (New York, N.Y.).
  The New York Metro Area Postal Union (American Postal Workers Union, Local 10) represents clerks, motor vehicle staff, maintenance workers and mail-handlers in the greater New York City area. In 1973 the union changed its name to the New York Metro Area Postal Union, from the Postal Union of Manhattan-Bronx Clerks, the new name reflecting the inclusion of the New York Bulk and Foreign Mail Center and the North Jersey Facility in the local's bargaining unit. The website contains news listings, their health plan, agreements, and other materials.
- New York State AFL-CIO Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; New York State AFL-CIO.
  The New York State AFL-CIO, in 1958, is the federation of labor unions in New York State affiliated with the AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations). The New York State AFL-CIO, in 1958, is the federation of labor unions in New York State affiliated with the AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations). The website contains information on their legislative action campaigns, press releases, regional and state news, endorsements, council members and other councils, and event listings.
- New York State Public Employees Federation Archived Website, Nov 5, 2011 - ongoing; New York State Public Employees Federation, AFL-CIO.
  Formed in 1978, New York State Public Employees Federation (PEF) is a local white-collar union, representing 55,599 professional, scientific, and technical public employees. PEF also represents employees who work in private-sector jobs and local government agencies including the Albany County Probation Department; Albany Housing Authority; NYS Canal Corporation; National Development and Research Inc; and, Lockport Memorial Hospital. The union publishes The Communicator, a newsletter with a 2007 distribution of 70,000, on a monthly basis
  Public employees.
- New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) Archived Website, Feb 13, 2013 - ongoing; New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)
  New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) is a 600,000-member New York state teachers union, affiliated since 2006 with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT), the AFL-CIO, and the National Education Association (NEA). NYSUT is a federation of over 1200 local unions in New York state; lobbies on the local, state and federal level; conducts research; and organizes new members. The website contains a blog, information in benefits, by-laws and contracts, and other resources.
  Teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- New York Taxi Workers Alliance Archived Website, May 6, 2011 - ongoing; New York Taxi Workers Alliance.
  New York Taxi Workers Alliance, founded in 1998, consists of 15,000 members of yellow taxicab drivers. NYTWA provides legal, health and financial services and improve working conditions through organizing, political and media advocacy, litigation, direct legal services, and access to healthcare. They are part of the Central Labor Council and the International Taxi Workers Alliance. The website contains information on current campaigns, membership information, press releases, event listings, and a blog.
  Taxicab workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Taxicab workers |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Newspaper Guild of New York, CWA Local 31003 Archived Website, Feb 5, 2009 - ongoing; Newspaper Guild of New York.
  The Newspaper Guild of New York, launched in 1934, is an labor union for people in the news and media business, including print, photo, video, and digital journalists, as well as employees in advertising, circulation and other related areas. They represent about 3,000 employees at New York area-based media organizations and their respective bureaus around the nation.
  Newspaper employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Reporters and reporting--New York (State)--New York.
- Office and Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Office and Professional Employees International Union.
  Office and Professional Employees International Union is a trade union representing over 110,000 white-collar workers in the public and private sector, including workers in banking and credit unions, insurance, higher education, shipping, hospitals, medical clinics, utilities, transportation, hotels, and administrative offices. Professional organizations and Guilds affiliated with OPEIU are a diverse group that includes physicians, pharmacists, chiropractors, appraisers, podiatrists, clinical social workers, hypnotists, teachers, and helicopter pilots.
  White collar workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Operative Plasterers' and Cement Masons' International Association of the United States and Canada (OP&CMIA) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2009 - ongoing; Operative Plasterers' and Cement Masons' International Association of the United States and Canada
  The Operative Plasterers' and Cement Masons' International Association of the United States and Canada (OPCMIA), founded in 1864, is a trade union of plasterers and cement masons in the construction industry in the United States and Canada. Members of the union finish interior walls and ceilings of buildings and apply plaster on masonry, metal, and wire lath or gypsum. Cement masons are responsible for all concrete construction, including pouring and finishing of slabs, steps, wall tops, curbs and gutters, sidewalks, and paving. The organization is a member union of the AFL–CIO and Canadian Labour Congress.
- Organization of Staff Analysts Archived Website, Feb 9, 2013 - ongoing; Organization of Staff Analysts.
  Founded in 1970 by twelve employees of the New York City Department of Personnel as the Committee of Personnel Examiners, the Organization of Staff Analysts (OSA) became the official collective bargaining agent for Analysts in the Board of Education in 1985. OSA is a member of, and bargains collectively through, the Municipal Labor Committee. It represents employees of the City of New York in the Analyst title series serving in more than fifty city agencies. The website contains information on benefits, newsletter, and weekly newsline.
  Civil service |z New York (State) |z New York.; Collective bargaining |x Government employees |z New York (State) |z New York; Government employee unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; White collar workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.